rainier.com 2014-07-01

# Privacy Policy - Rainier Industries

Rainier is aware of the trust you place in us and our responsibility to protect your privacy. We are committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the Rainier websites and governs data collection and usage. By using the Rainier websites, you consent to the data practices described in this statement. Our goal is to be a responsible steward of any information that we may obtain.

### Collection of your Personal Information

Rainier may collect personal information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. Rainier also collects anonymous demographic information, which may not be unique to you, such as your ZIP code, product interest, referral source, etc.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by Rainier. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring websites addresses. This information is only used by Rainier for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Rainier website.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through any Rainier website public areas, this information may be collected and used by others.

Rainier encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from Rainier so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. Rainier is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the Rainier websites.

### Use of your Personal Information

Rainier collects and uses your personal information to operate the Rainier website and deliver the services you have requested. Rainier may also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Rainier and its affiliates. Rainier may contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

Rainier does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. We may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to any third party. In addition, Rainier may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Rainier, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Rainier does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations.

Rainier websites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Rainier or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Rainier; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Rainier, or the public.

### Use of Cookies

The Rainier website uses “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Rainier pages, or register with Rainier site or services, a cookie helps Rainier to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same Rainier website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the Rainier features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Rainier services or Web sites you visit.

### Security of your Personal Information

Rainier secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Rainier secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

### Update your Personal Information

Rainier wants to ensure we keep only the most accurate and up-to-date information about you in our records. Therefore, whenever you believe that your contact information needs to be updated, please contact us at [customerservice@rainier.com](mailto:customerservice@rainier.com) to correct or update your contact information.

### Contact Information

Rainier welcomes your comments and questions regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that Rainier has not adhered to this Statement, please contact Rainier at [customerservice@rainier.com](mailto:customerservice@rainier.com).
